{"tossups": [{"question": "Event and type of location required. In Brooklyn in 1876, almost 300 people died in one of these events, whose victims were mostly from the upper family circle. Eddie Foy tried to calm the crowd during one of these events at Chicago\u2019s Iroquois in 1903, but over 600 people died, making it the deadliest of these events in history. In the opinion to 1919\u2019s<em> Schenck v. United States</em>, Oliver Wendell Holmes, Jr. wrote that \u201cthe most stringent protection of free speech would not protect\u201d someone from falsely shouting that one of these events was occurring. For the point, name this specific type of disaster, one of which destroyed Shakespeare\u2019s Globe after a cannon accident.", "answer": "<b> theater fire</b> (accept descriptions of indoor venues for plays, musicals, and/or concerts, but <em>not</em> movies, for \u201ctheater;\u201d prompt on partial answers, such as \u201cfire\u201d or \u201cdisaster in a theater;\u201d prompt on stampede, human crush, etc. before \u201cfalsely shouting\u201d is read)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "The book<em> Spartans in Darkness</em> analyzes signal intelligence\u2019s role in an event in this body of water. James Stockdale led a group of aircraft from the<em> Ticonderoga</em> on a bombing run during a DESOTO patrol in this body of water. Wayne Morse was one of only two senators to oppose a law, named after this body of water, that granted Lyndon Johnson the power to deploy American troops in Southeast Asia. The <em>Turner Joy</em> and the<em> Maddox</em> were attacked by torpedo boats in, for the point, what gulf off the coast of North Vietnam?", "answer": "Gulf of<b> Tonkin</b> (accept Gulf of<b> Tonkin</b> Resolution; prompt on South China Sea)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "A leader of nationalist resistance in this country was nicknamed \u201cThe Big Fellow\u201d and employed a hit squad nicknamed the \u201cTwelve Apostles.\u201d The Croke Park and Phoenix Park massacres occurred in this country, where British irregulars known as the \u201cBlack and Tans\u201d were deployed to crush nationalist resistance. The leaders of this country\u2019s independence movement included Michael Collins and Eamon de Valera. For the point, name this country where in 1920, British soldiers murdered spectators at a Gaelic football match in Dublin.", "answer": "Republic of<b> Ireland</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {"question": "This man executed an entire local populace after nobody confessed to writing a message on a fallen meteor predicting his death. This man standardized his country by introducing the Ban Liang coin and the small seal script. Sima Qian [chee-ahn] accused this man of burying Confucian scholars alive, but he probably only murdered priests and shamans who misled him about immortality. Li Si was employed by, for the point, what proponent of Legalism, the first Emperor of China?", "answer": "Qin<b> Shi Huang</b>di (accept<b> Ying</b> Zheng; accept<b> Zhao</b> Zheng; accept<b> King Zheng</b> of Qin) Page 2", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {"question": "This author wrote about a watchmaker and a draper who choose to be executed rather than to give up a password to enemy forces in his story \u201cTwo Friends.\u201d Rachel hides in a bell tower after stabbing a drunken officer to death in this author\u2019s story \u201cMademoiselle Fifi.\u201d The prostitute Elizabeth Rousset flees during the Franco-Prussian War in this author\u2019s story \u201cBall of Fat.\u201d For the point, name this French author who wrote about a piece of fake jewelry in \u201cThe Necklace?\u201d", "answer": "Guy de<b> Maupassant</b>", "metadata": "Literature - European Literature - Short Fiction"}, {}, {"question": "Dedications at this site include a memorial to the victims of the Pan Am Flight 103 bombing at the Lockerbie Cairn, as well as a memorial built from the mast of the sunken USS<em> Maine</em>. John Carl Warnecke designed an eternal flame at this site in honor of John F. Kennedy. Recipients of the Silver Star or Purple Heart meet the criteria to be buried at, for the point, what national military cemetery across the Potomac River from Washington DC?", "answer": "<b> Arlington</b> National Cemetery", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "The Geary Act required people of this ethnicity to carry internal passports. Workers of this ethnicity were killed in the Rock Springs Massacre, primarily by members of the Knights of Labor, and were opposed by Denis Kearney\u2019s Workingmen\u2019s Party. Reneging on the Burlingame Treaty allowed the US to forbid immigration from these people\u2019s home country, which was done in 1882. For the point, name this ethnicity, the subject of a namesake Exclusion Act, whose workers were exploited in building the Pacific end of the transcontinental railroad.", "answer": "<b> Chinese</b> Americans Page 3", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "In medieval times, the center of this city, Carpentras, was found within the Comtat Venaissin. The plans of Gregory XI to leave this city were halted by a conflict with Florence called the War of the Eight Saints. The Western Schism began after a major religious office was removed from this city in 1376, ending the period dubbed the Babylonian Captivity. For the point, name this French city to which Clement V moved the home of the Papacy.", "answer": "<b> Avignon</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {"question": "Ren\u00b4e Descartes was employed by Christina, a Queen of, for the point, what country that she ruled from Stockholm?", "answer": "<b> Sweden</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "After this battle, Sir Charles Asgill was captured and supposedly mistreated. According to separate legends, this battle\u2019s opening cannon shots destroyed both the ship<em> Guadeloupe</em> and a dinner table where enemy officers were eating. One side in this battle lost control of Redoubts 9 and 10 after their supply lines were cut by a naval defeat at Chesapeake. The song \u201cThe World Turned Upside Down\u201d allegedly played after the surrender at, for the point, what 1787 battle where Cornwallis surrendered to Washington, the last major battle of the American Revolution?", "answer": "Battle of<b> Yorktown</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "During this period, a system of five ranks of nobility called the kazoku was created, and the rigid class system was abolished by the Charter Oath. Two southern provinces, Satsuma and Choshu, allied during the Boshin War, whose end solidified the reforms of this period. This period began after the arrival of Matthew Perry\u2019s \u201cblack ships\u201d and the signing of the Convention of Kanagawa. For the point, name this 19th century period of modernization in Japan, when the namesake emperor was restored to the throne.", "answer": "<b> Meiji</b> Restoration (accept equivalents for Restoration, like Revolution, Reform, etc.; accept <b>Meiji</b> period, era, etc.) Page 4", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "APX enzymes use this compound as an electron donor. James Lind pioneered the use of clinical trials with a study on a key use of this compound. Albert Szent-Gyorgyi and Walter Haworth were awarded a Nobel Prize for the discovery of this compound, which was the first ever vitamin to be manufactured. Use of this vitamin to combat cancer and the common cold was promoted by Linus Pauling. A lack of this vitamin causes collagen instability, which led to many sailors developing scurvy. For the point, name this vitamin found in citrus fruit like oranges.", "answer": "Vitamin<b> C</b> (accept<b> ascorbic acid</b>)", "metadata": "Science - Biology"}, {}, {"question": "The 2nd Division unit dedicated to the use of this technology won a decisive American victory in the Battle of Norfolk. In 1980, the U.S. introduced a new generation of these weapons named after Creighton Abrams. The M4 variety of these weapons, used extensively in World War II, was named after William T. Sherman. George Patton commanded the first American unit dedicated to the use of these weapons in World War I. For the point, name these armored battle vehicles.", "answer": "<b> tank</b>s (accept additional information, such as Abrams<b> tank</b> after Abrams is mentioned)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "The Yongzheng Emperor required everyone taking the civil service examination to learn this city\u2019s dialect of Mandarin. This city was the site of the Siege of the International Legations, which caused the deployment of the Eight Nation Alliance during the Boxer Rebellion. The Qing dynasty\u2019s seat of power was the Forbidden City in, for the point, what capital of China?", "answer": "<b> Beijing</b> (accept<b> Peking</b>)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "Sculptural depictions of one member of this profession are classified as Type A or Type B; Type B works are inspired by a bronze statue made by Lysippos. Another man of this profession wears a white robe and gold, sash-like chain and rests his hand on a bust in a dark portrait by Rembrandt. In a painting by Jacques-Louis David, a member of this profession holds a cup and points upward as his friends and followers lament. For the point, name this profession of the central figure of<em> The Death of Socrates</em>.", "answer": "<b> philosopher</b>s Page 5", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Visual Fine Arts"}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "This is the home state of President Trump\u2019s first Agriculture Secretary who, in 2003, became this state\u2019s first Republican governor since Reconstruction. A Congressman from this state became Speaker of the House in 1995 after working with Texas\u2019 Dick Armey on the \u201cContract with America.\u201d This state was governed by a Democrat in the early 1970s who later beat Gerald Ford to become President. For the point, name this home state of politicians like Sonny Perdue, Newt Gingrich, and Jimmy Carter.", "answer": "<b> Georgia</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "A man in this political position wrote a letter to Rajiv Gandhi apologizing for the Air India Flight 182 bombing. Hugh Allan bribed a man with this position in the Pacific Scandal. A man in this position said, \u201cJust watch me,\u201d while facing a terrorist incident in the October Crisis. Kim Campbell was the only woman to hold this position, which was first held by Sir John A. MacDonald. For the point, name this highest position in Canada\u2019s government, currently held by Justin Trudeau.", "answer": "<b> Prime Minister</b> of<b> Canada</b> (prompt on partial answers, like \u201cPrime Minister\u201d or \u201cleader of Canada\u201d) Page 6", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "This activist donated a portion of land to the AME Zion Church to establish a home for the elderly. During one mission, this woman pulled out a revolver and threatened a man \u201cyou go on or die.\u201d William Lloyd Garrison gave a religious nickname to this woman, who never ran her \u201ctrain off the track\u201d or \u201clost a passenger.\u201d For the point, name this woman, nicknamed Moses, who assisted dozens of slaves as a conductor on the Underground Railroad.", "answer": "Harriet<b> Tubman</b> <b>Extra Question</b> Only read if moderator botches a question.", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "Two answers required. The Walwal incident erupted between these two countries after one built a fort in disputed territory. Disputes over the interpretation of the Treaty of Wuchale [woo-chal-ay] triggered another conflict between these nations. One of them invaded the other after the League of Nations failed to decisively resolve the Abyssinia Crisis. Menelik II prevented one of these countries from colonizing the other with a victory at the Battle of Adwa. For the point, name these two countries that also fought in the 1930s under Haile Selaisse and Benito Mussolini.", "answer": "Kingdom of<b> Italy and</b> the<b> Ethiopia</b>n Empire (accept<b> Abyssinia</b> for Ethiopia before\u201cAbyssinia\u201d is read) Page 7", "metadata": "History - World History"}], "bonuses": []}